

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

5032 Forbes Avenue, SMC 4936, Pittsburgh, PA 15289, USA

□ (+1) 412-657-2741 | **I**fzeng@andrew.cmu.edu | **A** https://fanpu.io | **D** fanpu | **D** zengfanpu

# **Summary** \_

I have 8 months of experience working in a seed-round startup (Saleswhale) that provided me with experience in web development in production, working in cross-functional teams, and translating product requirements into technical features. I am interested to work on things related to the backend, site reliability engineering, scale problems, automation, and infrastructure. I love startups, DevOps, automating things, and I am a big fan and user of Arch Linux.

# **Education**

### **Carnegie Mellon University**

Pittsburgh, PA, USA

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

Aug. 2018 - Expected May. 2022

- Activities: Plaid Parliament of Pwning (Cybersecurity & CTF competitions), CMU Math Club
- GPA: 4.0

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

## Saleswhale (YC S16)

Singapore, Singapore

JR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Regularly delivered core product features and bug fixes for the main Saleswhale app with Rails, Ember.js, RSpec, Redis, Sidekiq. Contributed
  to product meetings and sign-offs.
- Empowered our Customer Success team in performing account onboarding, management, and health reporting by architecting and building an internal tool from scratch with Rails, Ember.js, Rspec, SemanticUI, Gulp. Took ownership of it and regularly updated it to support the internal operational requirements of our product roadmap and in response to user feedback
- Drastically reduced product testing times and accelerated feature releases by building and automating the deployment of a testing framework micro-service with Rails, AWS SQS, Docker, Fabric from scratch to mock the asynchronous operations of another bottleneck micro-service
- Took charge of engineering support tickets filed by other departments related to codebase that I am familiar with, and to investigate, prepare, and deploy a fix if necessary
- Helped the Operations team meet key SLAs by developing a Tableau workbook from scratch to return insights on operational metrics and performance
- In charge of the algorithms & data structures segment of the technical interview for hiring new software engineers, and also helped to onboard new engineers to the codebase

**SWAT** Singapore, Singapore

RESEARCH INTERN

Jan. 2017 - Mar. 2017

- · Helped to drive insights for the company's expansion strategy by finding pertinent datapoints via clustering large transport data
- Sought to find best clustering method to yield useful datapoints. Research report included details on data exploration and cleaning, data transformation, comparison of clustering algorithms (K-means, K- medoids, DBSCAN, Hierarchical clustering), and optimization of clustering parameters.
- Developed an end-to-end solution in R to perform the above.

### **Hwa Chong Institution**

Singapore, Singapore

INSTRUCTOR

Oct. - Dec. 2016, Oct - Dec. 2017

- Instructor of Hwa Chong Institution's (HCI) Informatics Olympiad team
- Conducted weekly lectures and practice contests for around 20 students to prepare them for the National Olympiad in Informatics (NOI)
- Helped to achieve HCl's best ever performance in NOI in 2018, with 6 Golds and 3 Silvers from a team of 10. HCl was also ranked first in Junior College category

### **Singapore Armed Forces**

Singapore, Singapore

Jan. 2016 - Nov. 2017

COMPANY QUARTERMASTER SERGEANT

- Commands and oversees the logistics division in 'J' Company, Specialist Cadet School
- Ensure the requisition, accounting, maintenance, and distribution of supplies to troops

# Honors & Awards

2018	First Place, Home Invasion 2018 (IoT-CTF)	Singapore
2018	Silver Award, Cyber Defenders Discovery Camp	Singapore
2018	Winner, People's Choice, NUS Hack&Roll 2018	Singapore
2015	Silver Award, National Olympiad in Informatics	Singapore
2015	Gold Award (Equity Portfolios: Essentials of a Winning Portfolio), Singapore Science and Engineering Fair	Singapore
2014	Champion, Best Use of Open Data, Splash Awards	Singapore

January 9, 2019 Fan Pu Zeng · Résumé